Curriculum vitae Danil Annenkov

danil.v.annenkov@gmail.com +4581900892

GitHub: https://github.com/annenkov/ Personal page: https://dannenkov.me

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Birthdate: 16.11.1981.

Marital status: married, wife: Anna Annenkova.

Children: daughter Arina Annenkova.

Citizenship: Russia.

Current location: Aarhus, Denmark.

PROFILE

I am an experienced software developer working comfortably with multiple programming paradigms. I am especially interested in applications of functional programming, domain-specific languages, and proof assistants to make better software.

My recent focus at Concordium is the Rust/Wasm stack for smart contracts and integration of cryptographic libraries from the Rust ecosystem (e.g. <u>dalek cryptography</u> and <u>artworks</u>) into the Concordium infrastructure. As part of the internal science team, I also participated in specifying a zero-knowledge query language used in the Concordium ID layer and the verifiable credentials framework.

I have research and development experience related to the financial domain: I studied stochastic models of financial instruments during my master's and later, during my Phd studies, I accompanied this knowledge with a domain-specific language for financial contracts. My recent experience is related to another form of contract language: smart contracts for blockchains.

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Scientist (current employment)

from September 2022

At Concordium, Aarhus, Denmark

R&D in smart contract technology and formal methods. Software development in Rust.

Specifications for Concordium's verifiable credentials framework. Integration of Rust cryptographic libraries into the Concordium's infrastructure.

Postdoc Researcher December, 2018 - August 2022

At COBRA, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark

Postdoc Researcher February, 2018 - November, 2018

At INRIA, Nantes, France

PhD Fellow/Research Assistant November, 2014 - January, 2018

At The University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark

Founder of a Software Development Company

2009 - 2014

Web-based enterprise solutions

(CRM, Service Department Information System, e-Commerce)

Python/Javascript Developer

September 2013 - January 2014

At Exploriana Inc., remote.

Member of the guidemore.com development team.

Part-time teacher 2010 - 2012

At Irkutsk State Technical University, Russia

Programmer 2004 - 2005

At Railroad Clinical Hospital, Irkutsk, Russia

Deployment of a medical information system

DevOps/Programmer

At Demetra, Irkutsk, Russia 2002 - 2004

Windows/Novell Netware administration

Software Development: Delphi, InterBase RDBMS

Research Assistant 2002 - 2006

At Irkutsk State Technical University, Russia

EDUCATION

PhD, University of Copenhagen, DIKU

2014 - 2017

Graduated with distinction from Irkutsk State Technical University,

Faculty of Cybernetics, Department of Automated Systems (5 of 5 years)

(equivalent to a master's degree)

July, 2002

SKILLS

10+ years of programming experience (both industry and academic).

Programming languages

Functional programming languages: Haskell, Scala, Racket (Lisp).

Smart contract languages: CameLIGO (Tezos), Liquidity (Dune), Solidity (Ethereum), Rust (Concordium)

Other: Java, Python, JavaScript, Rust, Matlab, Object Pascal, Borland Delphi.

Proof assistants

Coq, Lean, Agda

Version control systems

Svn, Git, Mercurial

Team Leadership

Was a team leader for a small group of developers (3-4 persons).

Misc

Have experience with agile development techniques, testing, and continuous integration.

ACADEMIC PUBLICATION SUMMARY

Google Scholar statistics: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=JjtxzfkAAAAJ&hl=en

Publications 20 Citations 203 h-index 7 I10-index 5

Publications in top journals and conferences on formal verification and functional programming:

- Journal of Functional Programming (JFP)
- International Conference on Functional Programming (ICFP)
- Conference on Certified Programs and Proofs (CPP)
- Principles and Practice of Declarative Programming (PPDP)

SOFTWARE

1. Concordium's smart contract framework

- Integrating a property-based testing library
- Developing new smart contracts for the Concordium ecosystem.
- Improving documentation.
- Collecting and documenting best practices for developing smart contracts for the Concordium blockchain.
- Smart contract code review, including external partners.
- Integrating new cryptographic libraries into the Concordium infrastructure.

Technology: Rust, property-based testing, Cryptographic libraries.

Project repositories:

- https://github.com/Concordium/concordium-rust-smart-contracts
- https://github.com/Concordium/concordium-base

2. ConCert

(one of the main contributors)

A framework for smart contract verification in and code extraction from the Coq proof assistant.

- A verified embedding for a functional language into Coq.
- An execution model formalisation for functional smart contract languages.
- Code extraction to functional smart contract languages (Dune Liquidity, Tezos -CameLIGO, Concordium - Rust) and general-purpose languages (Rust, Elm).

Project repository: https://github.com/AU-COBRA/ConCert

Some stats: ~50 KLOC, 6 contributors, 3 master's projects, 4 papers (3 co-authored), industrial collaboration with Concordium and Tezos, academic collaboration with MetaCoq team (INRIA) and Futhark team (DIKU).

CONTRIBUTIONS TO OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

1. Contract DSL

(contributed as part of my PhD)

Extensions of the domain-specific language for financial contracts by Patrick Bahr, Jost Berthold and Martin Elsman. "Certified Symbolic Management of Financial Multi-Party Contracts". ICFP'2015. Compilation of the DSL to the intermediate Payoff language implemented in the Coq proof assistant.

Technology: the Cog proof assistant, Haskell.

Project repository: https://github.com/annenkov/contracts

2. The HIPERFIT Portfolio Management Prototype

(developed as part of my PhD, used for bachelor's projects)

A web-based system that integrates the Contract DSL and the HIPERFIT parallel pricing engine (FINPAR). The system is written in Haskell and features automatic web-form generation on the base of Haskell data types along with OpenCL code generation for payoff functions.

Technology: Haskell, OpenCL.

Project repository: https://github.com/HIPERFIT/prototype

3. MetaCoq

(contributed as part of the ConCert project development)

Meta-programming in Coq and formalisation of the meta-theory of Coq in Coq. Contributed with the support for definitionally proof-irrelevant propositions (SProp) in MetaCoq, after SProp was added to Coq.

Technology: the Cog proof assistant.

Project repository: https://github.com/MetaCog/metacog/

LANGUAGES

Russian - native

English - fluent (IELTS score 7.0 in 2014)

Danish - completed DU3 (PD3 exam), corresponds to the B2 level of CEFR (according to uim.dk)